<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iot on Random Musings</title>
    <link>https://mabsimms.github.io/tags/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iot on Random Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 11:22:54 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mabsimms.github.io/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration through Specification</title>
      <link>https://mabsimms.github.io/2018/05/09/integration-through-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 11:22:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mabsimms.github.io/2018/05/09/integration-through-specification/</guid>
      <description>Successful delivery of an IoT project at scale brings together multiple areas of expertise, processes and organizations. Each of the individual components carry with them assumptions and assertions about how the world works, and how product is designed, implemented (or manufactured).
Take the simple example of a home thermostat - involving embedded device manufacture, firmware development and maintenance, cloud connectivity, distibuted back-end services and mobile applications. In the small this could involve a small development team adapting off the shelf hardware; in the large this could be multiple divisions of a multi-national corporation outsourcing individual sub-components with strict information and awareness firewalls between delivery teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Patterns for Internet of Things Applications</title>
      <link>https://mabsimms.github.io/2018/05/09/anti-patterns-for-internet-of-things-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 11:20:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mabsimms.github.io/2018/05/09/anti-patterns-for-internet-of-things-applications/</guid>
      <description>Over the past eight years I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to work on a wide variety of Internet of Things (IoT) applications, from automobiles, to beverage machines, thermostats and everything in between.
While there are always specific aspects and challenges in any large scale IoT project delivery, I&amp;rsquo;ve run into the same set of six or seven key anti-patterns on nearly every project. While I&amp;rsquo;ve had a deck floating around in various engagements for a couple of years, had enough asks to sit down and flesh it out in a readable (hopefully :) form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>